

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Marco António Lopes Pinto, 26 years old. Living in Porto, nowadays. Motivated in the development of new skills technologies. and new Willingness to face new challenges and great adaptability to any project. Always in a good mood, ready to learn and recognize mistakes, with great group dynamics.

CONTACT

- marco.alp120@gmail.com
- +351 963 691 000
- in /mrcoalp

SOFT SKILLS

- Exceptional communication and networking skills
- Successful working in a team environment, as well as independently
- The ability to work under pressure and multi-task
- The ability to follow instructions and deliver quality results
- Ease of arguing and exposing formed opinions
- · Very meticulous when executing a task
- Consistently seeking and learning new technology
- Organizational skills developed in an academic environment
- Quick adaptation to new challenges and willingness to learn more and more
- Great problem solver
- Experience in sales and customer interaction
- Experience of teaching acquired through private music lessons in various institutions
- Experience in musical entertainment, acquired in several musical projects as a guitarist and singer

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Object-oriented programming
- Work within an agile Kanban team
- Web development
- Experiene in bash/cmd/powershell commands
- Familiar with UI Toolkits and Frameworks

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS/TECHNOLOGIES

- Java, Kotlin, SQL, Dart, HTML, Javscript, Typescript, CSS, C#, Python
- .NET, Flutter, Angular, Bootstrap, Django, Ionic, Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

Beanstalk-TI, Software Engineer

JAN 2019 - PRESENT

- Development of multiple mobile applications, cross-platform, using technologies such as IONIC and Flutter as frontend and .NET in backend. These apps integrate with an API and retrieve information through http requests. They can also access camera, mic, storage and location of the device [both iOS and Android using native code (Kotlin, Swift)] and send that data through the API
- Web development in Angular 7 of a web store for printing companies
- Integration into multi-person projects

Personal Mobile App Project

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

 Cross-platform mobile app that suggests random movies based on filter specs. The app contains user profile to store favourite movies, watched ones and watchlist. Same with TV Series. Using Flutter for client side implementation and .NET for server side. The data is stored using SQL Server. Rest api with JWT security as interface client-server.

PDT - Visabeira Global, Commercial Manager

SEP 2018 - JAN 2019

- Raising and managing clients for the telecommunications company NOS.
- Communication Skills and Product Exposure.

Musician

2011 - PRESENT

• Several musical projects where I participate as guitarist and/or singer

EDUCATION

RSL Level 3 Certificate In Popular Music Performance Grade 8 – Electric Guitar

JAHAS Rockschool, Porto (Portugal) | 29/11/2016

Bachelor of Science in Engineering - Profile of Engineering Informatics and Computing

Faculdade de Engenharia da Universidade do Porto | 2011 - 2015 Nível 6 QRQ

RSL Level 3 Certificate In Popular Music Performance Grade 5 – Electric Guitar

JAHAS Rockschool, Porto (Portugal) | 30/11/2014

Scientific-Humanistic Course of Sciences and Technologies Externato D. Afonso Henriques, Resende | 2008 - 2011

Native language

Portuguese

Foreign languages

English - Listening, Reading - Advanced Level; Oral interaction, Oral production, Writing - Independent Level

French - Listening, Reading, Oral interaction, Oral production, Writing - Basic Level